### **Ahmet OZKESEK**

Ground Floor Flat 17 Stonor Road W14 8RZ LONDON

M: 0772 922 3112

E: aozkesek@gmail.com

### **Profile**

I am 25+ years experienced Software Developer/Programmer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering. I developed, planned and designed various software for Contact Centre, ATM Management, Document Management and Workflow Management. I worked 16 years in Banking and Financial sector in Istanbul-Turkey. Now, I am seeking a Software Developer role in London where I can continue to improve myself in English.

# **Key Skills**

- Java 8 SE Oracle Certified Professional (OCP)
- C#, C, JavaScript
- Oracle, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL Relational DB
- Iunit, TestNG, Selenium Test Driven Development
- Gradle, Maven, Git, Docker
- Spring Framework Java EE, Hibernate ORM, JSF & Primefaces, Apache Struts, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, PostSharp
- ITAPI & Cisco, Genesys CTI & IVR

## **Career History**

Oct 2016 - date	Istanbul - London	Freelancer

- Self studying Java EE
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-809 OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (81%)
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-808 OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (94%)
- Designing and developing an Android Video Chat Application for Language Learning while Role Playing https://github.com/aozkesek/p2p-cast
- Passed 1Z0-808 exam OCA Java 8 SE Programmer (94% on 2019.10.16) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate.pdf
- Designed and developed a Hospital Management Software with Biometric Verification for ZieZix360 from Nigeria. It was a Proof of Concept application that contains a Fingerprint and a Camera reader service module, multiple web service modules, and a web UI module. <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm">https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm</a> <a href="https://ziezix360.com/about-us/">https://ziezix360.com/about-us/</a>
- Developed some application for improving in Java, TDD <u>https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce</u> <u>https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner</u>

Jul 2014 – Aug 2016 NETAS, Istanbul	Consultant	
-------------------------------------	------------	--

- Designed and wrote Technical Design Document to submit a proposal for companies used Cisco Unified Communication and IP Desktop Phones.
- Created a prototype of IP Phone Service to join AVAYA Developer Connect Program
  - https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program\_benefits/overview/index.gsp
  - https://downloads.avaya.com/css/P8/documents/101026461
- Developed an IIS Management web application for Cisco IP Phone Service <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager">https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager</a>
   <a href="https://github.com/aozkesek/license-manager">https://github.com/aozkesek/license-manager</a>
- Trained the junior team members

Nov 2001 - Jan 2014	Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul	Senior Programmer
,	· ·	, <u> </u>

- Led a Workflow Management Development team for 3 months
- Developed and maintained workflow and document management service
- Developed and maintained automatic teller machine service
- Involved upgrading of contact centre infrastructure and hardware
- Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

Aug 1999 - Aug 2001	Demirbank, Istanbul	Programmer
---------------------	---------------------	------------

Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

### **Qualifications**

- OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (1Z0-809, 81%, 2020-01-30)
- OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (1Z0-808, 94%, 2019-10-16)
- Genesys, Istanbul, 2010: IP IVR Development Course
- Cisco, Istanbul, 2007: Cisco Unified Communication Manager Course
- Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul, 2005: Java Server Pages, MVC Apache Struts Course
- Genesys, San Fransisco, 2001: Genesys Certified Developer
- Netron, Istanbul, 1999: Internet Information Server (IIS), Active Server Page (ASP), Component Object Model (COM) Course

### Education

University of Istanbul, 1990 – 1997, Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering (<a href="http://bilgisayar.muhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr">http://bilgisayar.muhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr</a>)